Sean Martin

Brooklyn, NY • (718) 954-2949 • sean.r.martin@live.com • linkedin.com/in/sean-r-martin • Website: sean-r-martin.com

SUMMARY

I'm a senior software engineer with nearly 8 years of professional experience in both fullstack and backend positions. I've developed a track record of leading projects to completion (within my team as well across multiple teams), being a subject matter expert in areas of the codebase, and mentoring software engineers with less experience.

SKILLS

Python • JavaScript • Ruby • Rails • Django • FastAPI • React.js • Redux • jQuery • HTML5 • CSS3 • PostgreSQL • MySQL • Git • Webpack • Node.js • Express.js • Sequelize • Kafka

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - Ro (New York, NY)

Jan 2021 - Present

- Created APIs to support a new workflow for providers, which reduced the time spent on approving initial weight loss prescriptions by 50%.
- Reengineered the ID Verification process to use Kafka and a microservice, so it would scale and automatically retry in case of outages and/or errors. This process performs roughly 420k patient ID verifications per month.
- Launched a checkout page feature enabling bulk medication shipments, resulting in a \$29M increase in gross profit for the year.
- Upgraded the work permissioning system used by care providers, so they could get access to work based on their individual training and not just their job title. This enabled the onboard of over 160 new health practitioners.
- Launched a new ED product that led to the highest net new daily order requests in the company's history, beating the previous record by 7%.
- Engineered a new workflow to enable 30+ care team members to onboard 7 weeks earlier than otherwise able, so they could address a backlog of 37k units of work.
- Mentored 4 intermediate level software engineers on my team. Advised them on technical decisions, helped them debug issues, and monitored their progress on various multi-engineer projects.
- Interviewed over 25 candidates for engineering positions.
- Created the FE technical interview screening question used for software engineers.

Software Engineer - Sema4 (New York, NY)

Mar 2018 - Dec 2020

- Created a dashboard for employers to track and view the results of COVID-19 testing on their employees returning to work.
- Integrated a document upload feature to streamline the test result ordering process.
- Developed a network of conditionally rendering, self validating, and auto filling questions to improve the accuracy and completeness of the ordering form.
- Built an email notification system to alert users of new test results on a weekly, daily, or per result basis.
- Wrote technical specifications and determined the feasibility of new features.
- Provided production support for users ordering, tracking, and viewing test results.
- Advised and mentored other engineers on areas of the codebase where I'm a subject matter expert.

Software Engineer - J.P. Morgan Chase (Brooklyn, NY)

Jul 2017 - Feb 2018

- Improved and supported the company's market risk software platform.
- Maintained multiple QA testing environments to enable end-to-end testing of new features.
- Modified and tested software platform logic used to create market data reports.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

Baruch College (New York, NY) - B.B.A., Accounting (GPA: 3.9)

Certified Public Accountant (CPA) - New York State